Source Dragons!
You refuse me
my rightful place among you,
but ThunderFang
will not be denied!
[roaring]
[roar reverberating]
I will force myself
into your ranks,
and you will all pay
for your rejection of me!
[thunderous roaring]
[Lloyd groaning]
We gotta get
the Unbidden Storm
working again.
[Arin] It's impossible,
that thing's been spinning
for centuries.
I told you I'd find a way
to mess this up.
[Lloyd] I'm the one who caused
the cave-in, Arin, not you,
and remember,
Ninja never quit.
I'm not a Ninja anymore.
There's gotta be a way
to activate this thing again.
[♪♪♪]
This plan only works
with two halves of the dragon
combining
where the Unbidden Storm is.
Let's hope
everyone else did their part.
So... we just sit here
and wait to see
if ThunderFang
destroys everything?
[sighing]
Don't like this one bit.
[gasping]
I guess if these crystals
are glowing,
our half of the Arc Dragon
is still activated?
Which is good, right?
This is like flying blind.
We have no way of knowing
if the other teams succeeded.
[Sora] Kur?
Spectral Dragonians? Here?
This doesn't bode well
for the overall plan.
Well, fighting
is more fun than planning.
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[thunderclap]
I thought this was too easy.
We had to feed birds
who were secretly bells.
How is any of this easy?
I mean,
I need someone to fight.
[grunting with effort]
[unearthly shrieking]
[Kai grunting with effort]
Unh!
H'yah!
The problem with being
a backup copy of the Sorceress,
can't do magic.
I'm kind of useless in a fight.
Ooh, wait!
-[unearthly shrieking]
-Haah!
I've got it!
Throw me!
You sure?
It takes a lot
to hurt a coconut.
Do it!
[grunting with effort]
Yee-haw!
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Yes!
Look, Ma, no hands!
Whoo-hoo! This is
the most exciting thing
that's ever happened
to this version of me!
Y'ah! H'yah! H'ah!
H'yah!
ThunderFang really did
a number on you all.
Hope this frees your souls!
H'yah!
[Nya grunting with effort]
[stamping]
H'yah!
Zarkt's going to destroy
those crystals!
Then those crystals
must affect the Arc Dragon!
H'ah!
[roaring]
Let's hope this still works.
-[unearthly shrieking]
-Hup! H'yah!
How?
[Frak] Imperium tech.
H'yah!
I know Imperium's changed...
[unearthly shrieking]
...but just hearing those words
still gives me a chill.
[♪♪♪]
[stamping]
[Wyldfyre grunting with effort]
Ugly over there
is going to Shatterspin!
[♪♪♪]
[roaring]
ThunderFang's gotten
almost all the power
out of those things.
Come on, work!
[groaning]
It's no use!
I wonder if...
Hmm.
Not sure leaving your mech's
a good idea.
Dragonians could be here
any second.
Just let me try something.
[exhaling deeply]
Give me the Unbidden Storm!
Huh? How?
Just toss it!
[roaring battle cry]
Whoa...
I had no idea
you could transfer
your Object Spinjitzu
so... intensely.
That makes two of us,
but I've been training,
and it seemed like
our only option.
Now, let's finish the job.
Let's hope the other teams
pulled off their part.
[♪♪♪]
[Arc Dragon of Focus]
ThunderFang, we meet again.
[ThunderFang]
If you have been sent here
to challenge me,
the Source Dragons
must truly be afraid.
Why does everything look weird?
Are you also seeing, like,
a vision or something?
[ThunderFang snarling]
We're each seeing through
the eyes
of one of
the Arc Dragon's heads!
[ThunderFang] You may have
bested me last time,
but now I am more powerful
than I have ever been!
[roaring]
[cheering] Wa-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Right in the poppa!
[dragon roaring]
[Nya] Hey, ugly!
Made you look.
[dragon roaring]
ThunderFang!
[unearthly shrieking]
[Kai grunting with effort]
[Kai] How are we seeing that?
[Nya] We were right.
These crystals are connected
to the Focus Dragon.
I think we're seeing
through the dragon's eyes!
[roaring]
[snoring]
[unearthly shrieking]
[grunting with effort]
This is called
a set-up! Yaah!
[roaring]
[ThunderFang roaring]
...and that's called
the pay-off!
[unearthly shrieking]
[Frak grunting with effort]
[dream chorus chiming]
Sora, in case
we don't get out of this,
there's something
I need to tell you.
-What?
-I... um... I...
ate all the yogurt
in the monastery fridge.
[grunting with impact]
You... what?
I confess.
All of it, it's gone.
Great.
You're forgiven.
Why did I need to know this now?
Um, in case you make it out
and I don't,
and later somebody wonders
where all the yogurt went,
you'll have
a definitive answer.
[panting] Okay... weirdo.
[stamping]
[Sora] Kur's trying
Shatterspin again!
[Frak] Wyldfyre, heads up!
[unearthly shrieking]
I am not giving this back.
Keepsies!
[spin rumbling]
Yaah!
[stamping]
[groaning]
[Sora] No!
Ah! Oof!
H'yah!
[roaring]
[ThunderFang crying out]
[ThunderFang] You're nothing
but a lapdog of the Sources!
Puppet of corrupt masters!
I will soon be
the Eighth Source,
and I will rain chaos
across the Merged Lands!
[gasping]
[groaning]
I'm not just seeing
what the Focus Dragon sees,
I'm feeling what it feels,
and it hurts!
Yeah, didn't need
any more pain,
but does it feel like
the dragon wants our help?
Yeah, I sense it too.
Follow my lead.
[growling]
[grunting in pain]
[groaning]
You okay?
[grunting] I got this. Come on.
[gasping]
Yaah!
Oof!
[reverberating roar]
[both grunting with effort]
[roaring]
[groaning]
[ThunderFang snarling]
[grunting with effort]
H'ah! H'ah! H'ah! H'ah!
[grunting and straining]
Lloyd, I'm trying to stay
in sync with you,
but-- [grunting]
[roaring]
[panting]
[groaning]
[Lloyd] This isn't working.
The pain... I can't focus.
This is when you would tell me
Ninja never quit.
[groaning] We don't,
but we know when it's time
to change the plan.
Arin, you take the lead.
I'll follow you.
No. No way!
The Merged Lands
are at stake here.
I mess everything up!
You can do this.
Just focus.
Trust me, Arin.
[♪♪♪]
[neck cracking]
[growling]
[roaring]
[snarling]
Tell your masters
ThunderFang will reap veng--
[ThunderFang] Aah!
[groaning]
[Arc Dragon of Focus]
The battle is not over yet.
[grunting with effort]
Waah!
Oof!
Haah! Haah! Hi-yah!
[panting]
That all you got?
Aah! Whoa!
[gasping]
[Zarkt shrieking]
Nya!
[Nya shrieking]
[Kai shouting]
Haah! Aah!
[grunting with effort]
[unearthly shrieking]
[yelping]
[panting]
[spectral shrieking]
No!
Boo-yah! Take that!
[gasping] Jay?
You're one of my least
favorite people, Zarkt.
[♪♪♪]
Aah... haah!
I knew you'd come back, Jay.
I-I just happened
to be in the area.
[chuckling]
You just happened
to be deep in a cave
hidden behind
a magical waterfall?
Maybe. You don't know.
I could be really into caves,
or...
maybe you said some things
that stuck with me.
I don't remember you,
but being with you
makes me want to be...
not a terrible person.
[gasping]
[Kai grunting with effort]
Jay! That was amazing!
Forget everything I used to say
about you being the worst Ninja!
You used to say what?
Huh? What?
No, no, that was Cole.
We should go.
[unearthly shrieking]
[groaning]
[shrieking]
No...
[♪♪♪]
[together] Riyu!
[roaring]
[roar reverberating]
[grunting with effort]
H'yah! H'ah!
It's working!
[snarling]
H'ah! [blow thudding]
H'yah! [slamming]
[ThunderFang]
How dare you seven
keep all the power
for yourselves!
I belong amongst
the Source Dragons!
[together] Ninja...
Go!
[♪♪♪]
[ThunderFang groaning]
[cheering] Yeah!
[laughing and cheering]
[groaning]
Aah!
[roaring]
[muttering] Janet... Janet...
Aah! Whaa?
How did I get here?
Janet!
[♪♪♪]
[gasping in wonder]
[all gasping]
Well, these forms
aren't gonna stamp themselves.
[♪♪♪]
It's good
we're not hollow anymore.
Yeah, seriously.
Can you imagine
just mindlessly stumbling
through life like that?
[moaning]
Whoa! [sighing]
Yeah, I feel like
I missed something.
[all gasping in delight]
[laughing happily]
[Lee] Friends!
I've been a bad neighbor.
I've lied to you,
and it's time
I tell you all the truth...
[♪♪♪]
[gasping and groaning]
Fritz!
Spitz! Bonzle!
You're okay!
[♪♪♪]
[Arin] ThunderFang's gone?
We did it?
You did it, Arin.
[Arc Dragon of Focus]
You did well, mortals...
in waking me from my slumber,
and guiding me with your focus.
What'd I say?
[Arc Dragon of Focus] However,
my masters
may not feel the same way.
I return now to my slumber,
and pray the consequences
for your actions
are not too dire.
Well... that sounded ominous.
Arin, during the fight,
I was trying to force things
to go the way I wanted,
to control it all,
but now I realize,
I need to let go sometimes,
which also means...
letting go of you.
I can't force you
to become a Ninja, Arin.
[sighing heavily]
You don't have to, Lloyd,
because, after all this,
I realize I already am.
[♪♪♪]
If that's still okay with you.
[Lloyd] There's nothing
I want more.
[snoring]
[sighing] Still exhausted
from creating
that Arc Dragon, I see.
I feel them.
I could sleep for a week.
But Zanth is kinda...
our ride home.
We have other options.
The Monastery Gates, of course!
[low rumbling]
Whoa.
I'm suddenly light-headed
or something.
I feel weird too.
Is Djinjago tilting?
No, but something's off.
[low rumbling]
[Nya groaning]
[all groaning]
[Arin] ...but before
I get back to training,
I need a vacation
with my parents.
It's been so long.
Absolutely--
[groaning]
[low rumbling]
Are you okay?
[gasping]
I feel weird.
It's like my connection...
My elemental power.
Something's wrong with it.
What would cause that?
I don't know,
but we need to get back
to the Monastery...
now.
[♪♪♪]
[together] Ninjago!
[gasping]
This isn't right.
Whoa...
We're not in Ninjago.
Uh, the Gate took us
to the wrong place.
[door creaking shut]
[grunting with effort]
Why isn't it opening?
[locked handle rattling]
[pounding]
We're stranded here.
How could this happen?
[rattling]
Your former students
are lost now, old man,
scattered across
the farthest reaches
of the Merged Lands.
[rattling and banging]
Now nothing
will stand in my way.
[Energy] I would never
have believed
our siblings would do this.
Withdraw from the Council?
It's unthinkable.
[Flow] The mortals dared
command Focus's Arc Dragon,
her personal avatar.
Even you must admit
it was highly... improper.
[Motion] Improper, perhaps,
yet it saved this Council
from ThunderFang's wrath.
The Conduit
made the right choice.
[Energy] And yet it is
the mortals that will suffer.
With Focus, Life,
and Strength withdrawn,
the balance
of elemental powers is askew.
It will cause chaos
for the powers
of every Elemental Master
in the Merged Lands.
[Flow] Our promise
to the First Spinjitzu Master
is broken.
Source Dragons
violating their sacred word...
it may mean
the end of this cycle.
[Motion] Not just the end
of this cycle,
the end of all cycles.
The universe has never been
in more danger.
[Arin] We're trapped
who knows where,
the gates stopped working,
and your powers
are all messed up.
What are we gonna do, Lloyd?
What Ninja always do...
[♪♪♪]
...we'll find a way.